In this American English pronunciation video, we're going to learn how to make the RR as in bird sound.
在这段美式英语发音视频中，我们将学习如何发出像鸟一样的RR音。
I sometimes say this is the vowel version of the R consonant.
我有时会说这是R辅音的元音版本。
It's always followed by R, and there's no distinction between the sounds in American English.
在美式英语中，这个音总是跟随R，并且没有音的区别。
This sound will always be written with two different International Phonetic Alphabet, or IPA, symbols, but will be pronounced RR, just one sound, bird.
这个音总是用两个不同的国际音标符号书写，但会发成RR，只是一个音，像鸟一样。
To make this sound, the corners of the lips come in, pushing the lips away from the face.
要发出这个音，嘴唇的两角向内收，把嘴唇推离面部。
The middle part of the tongue lifts towards the roof of the mouth in the middle.
舌头的中部向口腔中间的上颚抬起。
The front of the tongue hangs down, but it's drawn back a bit, so it's not touching anything.
舌头的前部下垂，但稍微向后缩，所以没有接触到任何东西。
As the tongue lifts in the middle, it may be close to the roof of the mouth without touching it, or it may touch the sides of the roof of the mouth, or the insides or bottom of the top teeth, here.
当舌头中部抬起时，可能接近上颚但不接触，或者可能接触到上颚的两侧，或上牙的内侧或底部。
Rr, rr.
Rr, rr。
This, along with the R consonant, is one of the hardest sounds to make in American English.
这个音和R辅音一起，是美式英语中最难发出的音之一。
It's especially hard because the lip position hides the tongue position.
特别难是因为嘴唇的位置遮住了舌头的位置。
Let's take a look.
让我们来看一下。
From the side, we can't even see the tongue.
从侧面看，我们甚至看不到舌头。
The front view doesn't help much either.
正面视图也帮不了多少。
This is because the tongue goes back, but the lips flare forward.
这是因为舌头向后缩，但嘴唇向前张开。
Here's the word hurt.
这是单词hurt。
Watch the tongue pull back and up before coming forward for the T.
观察舌头在发T音前向后和向上拉。
In a stressed syllable, the RR vowel curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，RR元音先向上弯曲，然后向下。
Hurt.
Hurt。
Rr.
Rr。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调较低，同时更安静和更快。
Rr, rr.
Rr, rr。
The vowel is unstressed in the word research.
在单词research中，元音是非重读的。
Rr.
Rr。
Let's look at this word up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个单词。
The lips flare, but the jaw doesn't drop as much.
嘴唇张开，但下巴没有那么多下垂。
Let's compare the stressed RR in hurt on the top with the unstressed vowel in research on the bottom.
让我们比较一下上面的hurt中的重读RR和下面research中的非重读元音。
The lips flare for both, but in this case, there was much more jaw drop for the stressed version of this vowel.
两者的嘴唇都张开，但在这种情况下，重读版本的元音下巴下垂得更多。
This is typical.
这是典型的。
Stressed vowels are shorter, so there isn't as much time to make the full mouth position.
重读元音较短，所以没有那么多时间来完成整个口腔位置。
The RR vowel.
RR元音。
Stressed.
重读。
Hurt.
Hurt。
Rr.
Rr。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Research.
Research。
Rr.
Rr。
Rr, rr.
Rr, rr。
Unstressed words.
非重读单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Earth.
Earth。
Rr.
Rr。
Earth.
Earth。
Search.
Search。
Rr.
Rr。
Search.
Search。
Circle.
Circle。
Rr.
Rr。
Circle.
Circle。
Thirteen.
Thirteen。
Return.
Return。
Rr.
Rr。
Return.
Return。
Outburst.
Outburst。
Rr.
Rr。
Outburst.
Outburst。